<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
    Usable with FlightGear
    Property of Gerard Robin
    
    modified by HerbyW 2015

-->
<PropertyList>

        <title>Be-200Altair  Water dropping Jet Aircraft</title>
        
        <key>
	  <name>d</name>
	  <desc>Cargo Door open/close</desc>
	</key>
        <key>
	  <name>D</name>
	  <desc>close water tank doors</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>s</name>
	  <desc>Autostart</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>f</name>
	  <desc>Floats Up/Down</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>F</name>
	  <desc>Anchor</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>l (like "l"etter) </name>
	  <desc>release water over your target (water bombing)</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>L</name>
	  <desc>water loading pipes</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>B</name>
	  <desc>toggle ON/OFF Brake Parking</desc>
	</key>        
	<key>
	  <name>Delete</name>
	  <desc>Reverser on/off</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>&lt;</name>
	  <desc>Change Pilot Engineer View</desc>
	</key>
	<key>
	  <name>~</name>
	  <desc>Nose Wheel Steering</desc>
	</key>
<text>
WATER BOMBER Be-200 Altair Version: 3.0.2 by Herbert Wagner (HerbyW) 2015-2018

Press s for autostart.

Manual start up:
-all electrics on, 3 switches in upper position at middle panel
-all radios and instruments on, in overhead panel.
-press starter button and wait till green lamp is on,then switch engine on
-repeat with second engine
-set reference compass to marker position, at engineer panel

Filling of the water tank ( 12000 liters):
=> on water, the floats come automaticaly DOWN  (key"f")
=> prepare the filling before watering (command key  "L")
=> a speed minimum of 45 kts, 120 is fine
=> push gently the elevator, just enough to keep the aircraft sliding in the water
=> landing and starting on water with 3 or more flaps
=> hold the speed at 110-130 with nose in the air
=> The filling duration time is 18 sec.

Control your speed which must be more than 45 kts (if less it does not fill), more is better.
During the filling, the aircraft is getting more and more heavy.
When loaded  the weight of the aircraft is heavier of 12000 kg , remember it at take off,
you wants patience, and smooth piloting. Before climb, you must get the maximum of speed
with the help of the groundeffect, which is your friend.

For landing in water set 3 flaps, reducing speed to 110-130 kts.

Now you may simulate a water bombing
=> At a low agl, 200-500 ft, over the target which is supposed to be bombed,
=> release the water (command key 'l" like "l"etter)
The water can be seen falling down.
    
The  aircraft is right now 12000 kg less, it will jump upper in the sky, be prepared for it.
When empty don't forget to close the water tank doors ( key"D")
You may again, go back on the sea  and fill again, that process is repeatable as long as you wish it.

There are 3 placards in the middle panel: red, blue, white with description, so you do not need the shortcuts :)
    
Make fire in MP-Modus:
Activate all buttons in the Wildfire settings, to see the wildfire
(in this model is it done at startup automatically, for multiplayer each player has to set it to see it).
Press: Strg + Shift + click on the ground to make a fire, be aware that each fire gets bigger in time.

Refulling can only be done at ground, open the menue: Refuel

Liveboat control at the ramp panel with open cargo door.

Additional rudder-function in water.

All animations in multiplayer!

Have fun! HerbyW 2016
</text>

</PropertyList>